"Decryption"
HIDDEN LEAF
INTEL DIVISION
((フカサク : 最初は自来也ちゃんも
情報集めが目的で➡
Initially, Jiraiya-boy's purpose
was to gather intelligence.
ペインと戦うつもりは
なかったようじゃ。
It appears he never intended
to battle Pain.
じゃけど ペインの能力は
想像をはるかに超えとった。
But Pain's abilities far exceeded
his imagination.
あの男の能力が わからん以上➡
Unless we knew the scope
of his powers,
何度 戦うても
誰も勝てりゃあせん。
no one would ever be able
to defeat Pain.
自来也ちゃんは無理をしてのう。
Jiraiya-boy went beyond his own limits,
ペインの能力の正体を もう少しで
暴けるところまでいったんじゃ。
and almost managed to
uncover Pain's secrets.
自来也ちゃんじゃなけりゃ
そこまでも無理じゃった。
No one but Jiraiya-boy
could have gotten as far.
じゃけんじゃ 逃げようと思うたら
逃げられたのに➡
On top of that...
He could have escaped if he chose to.
Instead he sacrificed his life
to leave this coded message.
命と引き換えに
この暗号を残した。
(お前らに あとを託したんじゃ))
He entrusted the rest to you all.
(綱手)このカエルの中に➡
This frog supposedly contains
a captured Hidden Rain Ninja.
雨隠れの忍を
１人 拘束しているそうだ。
(イビキ)自来也様から 前もって
話は受けておりました。
We received prior notice
from Lord Jiraiya.
では 大きくなってくれ。
Now, grow.
少々 手荒でもかまわん。
Be as rough as you need to be.
Get everything you can from him!
すべてを聞き出せ！
そのつもりです。
I intend to.
AUTOPSY ROOM 3
SHIZUNE     OYONE     KUMADORI
(シズネ)自来也様が残された➡
This is one of the three crucial sources
of data Lord Jiraiya left us.
３つの情報のうちの
大切な１つです。
(シズネ)何がなんでも
手がかりを見つけますよ。
We must learn everything
we can from it.
- Yes, Ma'am!
さあ 始めます。
All right. Let's begin.
(シカマル)ずっと黙ったままだがよ。
You haven't said a word.
You see something, right?
なんか あんだろ？
(ナルト)う～ん。
五代目や カカシ先生に
あたってみたが➡
I talked to Lady Hokage
and Kakashi Sensei,
but neither of them had any clue.
何も知らなかった。
That means Lord Jiraiya probably
left this message with you in mind.
つまり 自来也様は お前に宛てて
暗号を残した気がするんだ。
No, I'm positive he did.
いや そうに違いない。
何か… 何か絶対にあるはずだ。
There's got to be something there.
(シホ)少しでも
気になることがあったら➡
If anything pops up in your mind,
tell us.
言ってみてください。 いきなり➡
We're not asking you to
instantly decode the message.
暗号を解読しろだなんて
言いませんから。
う～ん… 見たときから➡
There is one thing that's been
bothering me since I first saw this.
気になることはあったけど。
なんだ？
What is it?
Well...
うん なんで数字ばっかのなかに➡
There's all these numbers.
一文字だけ カタカナが
入ってんのかなと思ってさ。
So what's with this
one katakana letter?
Huh?
はぁ？
カタカナ？
Katakana?
どこに そんなもん…。
Where do you see that?
ほら ここ。
Right here.
どこがだよ？
そりゃ 数字の９だろ？
What are you talking about?
Isn't that the number "9"?
オレも最初は そう思ったけどよ。
That's what I thought at first...
これってば 数字の９じゃなくて
カタカナのタだってばよ。
But this is not the number "9."
It's the katakana letter "ta."
What?
う～ん そう言われりゃ➡
Well, I guess you could
look at it that way.
そう見えなくもねえけどよ
少し強引だろ。
But I think that's a big stretch.
《もしかして…》
I wonder...
うずまき君 ぶっちゃけ
どうして この９を➡
Uzumaki, what made you think
this nine was the katakana letter "ta"?
カタカナのタだと思ったんですか？
ああ エロ仙人てば
ずっと本 書いててさ…。
Well... Pervy Sage was writing books
all the time...
一応 作家だし。 んで オレは
ずっと一緒に旅してたから➡
He was an author, after all.
And I traveled all over with him.
He always made me read
his handwritten drafts,
手書きのやつを
ムリヤリ読まされていたんだよ。
感想を言えってさ。
and asked what I thought about them.
おもしろくはねえんだけど…。
They were really boring though...
((ふぁ～。
なんだ？
What the heck?
(９クティクスって？))
What's "Nine-ctics"?
で タの文字が出てきたとき
読みづらくってさ。
And whenever there was
the letter "ta," it was hard to read
なにしろ 数字の９みたいに
見えっから。
because it would look
like the number nine.
そうか 手癖！
I see... A penmanship quirk!
That was his habit, huh?
癖字ってわけか。
つまり こうか。
So what you're saying is...
自来也様は カタカナのタを書くとき
１画目を短く書く癖があって➡
When writing the katakana "ta,"
Lord Jiraiya had a habit of
shortening his first stroke.
１画目のおしりに
３画目がくっついてしまう。
So the first and third strokes
get connected.
それに ２画目が丸くなるから➡
And since he rounds
his second stroke,
それで タが９に見えてしまう。
it looks like the number nine.
Found it.
ありました。 え～と…。
Let's see...
これが 自来也様の筆跡です。
This is a sample of
Lord Jiraiya's writing.
(シカマル)同じだ！
It's the same!
自来也様は カタカナのタを➡
Lord Jiraiya knew that
Naruto would remember
数字の９のように
書いてしまう癖を➡
his habit of writing the katakana "ta"
like the number nine.
ナルト君なら見抜けると思った。
ぶっちゃけ それが➡
Frankly, this was the common link
between Lord Jiraiya and Naruto.
自来也様と うずまき君の
共通のカギだったんですよ！
なんで そんな大事なことを➡
Why didn't you mention such
an important thing sooner?!
気づいた時点で
さっさと言わねえんだよ!?
だって タってわかったからって
それが なんだってばよ？
Well, what's the big deal about
knowing that it's the letter "ta"?
そうか それだ！
That's it!
お前が
自来也様の原稿を読んだとき➡
It's when you were reading
Lord Jiraiya's manuscript
自来也様は お前が
自分の癖を知ったと思った。
that you found out about
his writing habit.
Then the code refers to that
book you were reading!
なら 暗号は
お前が言ってた その本だ！
本？
Book?
That's it, Shikamaru!
そ… それです シカマルさん！
そのとおり ぶっちゃけ➡
Right! Frankly, Lord Jiraiya's book
must contain a hint.
自来也様の本に
ヒントが隠されていると思います。
数字はおそらく 文字の順
行数か何か ページ数とか➡
Those numbers must represent
character numbers, line numbers
or page numbers.
絶対 このカギは
暗号と関係しています。
I'm certain they hold the key
to the code.
ナルト その本はどれだ？
Naruto, which book is it?
え～と イチャイチャ… なんだっけかな。
Umm... Hmm... Make-Out...
What was it?
なら 自来也様が
出版した本って何冊ある？
Well then, how many of
Lord Jiraiya's books have been published?
よくわかんねえけど
４～５冊かな？
I'm not sure... Four? Five?
とりあえず
その本を全部調べるぞ。
Then let's just check all of them!
(カカシ)それは
おそらく これのことだ。
It's probably this one.
MAKE-OUT TACTICS
(シカマル)『イチャイチャ タクティクス』の…。
Make-Out Tactics...
(みんな)タ！
- "Ta"?!
カカシ先生！
Kakashi Sensei!
気になって
こっちへ寄ってみたら➡
It's been on my mind,
so I decided to stop by when
I overheard your voices.
声が聞こえてきてな。
だいたいは聞かせてもらった。
I think I caught most of it.
お前たちが探しているのは
この本だろ。
This is the book you're looking for.
"Make-Out Tactics."
『イチャイチャ タクティクス』… そうだ！
That's right.
それが 修業で一緒に旅してた時に
エロ仙人が書いていた本だ。
That's the one Pervy Sage was
working on during our training.
なるほど ナルトじゃなきゃ
気づけなかったことだ。
I see... Only Naruto would've known that.
やっぱり自来也様は
ナルトに暗号を託してたんだ。
So Lord Jiraiya did pass
the key on to Naruto.
Uh-huh!
この暗号の最初のタの文字。
自来也様が書いた本のなかで➡
This "ta" is the first character
in the code.
Of Lord Jiraiya's books,
this is the only title that begins with "ta."
タが最初にくるのは
これしかない。
暗号に
文字が使用されている場合➡
When a character is used
in a code,
it could signify word placement
or line number,
文字の順や
行数とかもありますが➡
but the established protocol is
to check the page number first.
まずは最初に
ページ数を調べるのが定石です。
そうですね
点で区切ってある数字は➡
So...the numbers separated
by commas
31 ８ 106 ７➡
are 31, 8, 106, 7, 207, and 15.
Six sets.
207 15の６種類。
つまり ６ページ分の情報。
Meaning there are six pages
worth of information.
まずは31ページ
そこを開いてみてください。
Let's start with page 31.
Flip to that page, please.
31ページね… 開いた。
Page 31...
Okay, here it is.
で あとは どこを見るの？
Where do we look next?
こういう場合 まずは素直に
ページの頭文字を見ます。
In situations like this,
we look at the first character
on the page.
頭から一文を読み上げてください。
Please read the sentence out loud
starting from the top.
えっ!?
Wha-?
No... I mean...
いや あの…。
What is it?! Hurry up and read!
なんだってばよ！ いいから
早く読んでくれってばよ！
あ…。
早くしろってばよ！
Hurry it up!
ほ ほ… 本当に➡
"I-I-I...really...
あ あ… 愛してる。
love you."
CIPHER DIVISION
はい これで６ページ全部ですね。
どうだった？
There! We now have all six pages.
Well?
頭文字を暗号の順番どおりに
読んでいくと➡
If I read the first characters
of the code in order...
本 物 葉 意 無 椅
ってことになりますね。
The-Real-One's-Not-Among-Them...
That's what it says.
どういうこと？
わからん。
What does that mean?
I don't know.
We ought to relay this
to Lord Fukasaku.
ここは ガマのフカサク様に
連絡をつけてもらおう。
ペインと戦った本人なら
何か わかるかもしれない。
He fought with Pain,
so he may know something.
なら 五代目にすぐ➡
Then let's go right away
to the Lady Hokage
to ask this Lord Fukasaku to come.
そのフカサク様って人を
呼んでもらって…。
May I come along?
私も ついていっていいですか？
あぁ 頼む シホ。
はい！
Yeah, please do, Shiho.
Yes, sir!
All right! Let's go let Granny know!
よっしゃ！ さっさと
ばあちゃんに連絡だってばよ！
ホンモノハイナイ か。
"The-Real-One's-Not-Among-Them."
どうだ じいちゃん仙人
何か わかったか？
Well, Geezer Sage?! Anything?
((自来也 : あの６人のなかに➡
Of those six, not a single one
reminds me of Nagato.
長門の面影を感じる者は
１人もおりません。
だが 輪廻眼を持っていた長門と
わししか知らぬはずの会話を➡
Yet a completely unrelated Pain
knew of a conversation
that the Rinnegan-bearing Nagato
and I shared alone.
別のペインが知っていた。
(顔は違うが
長門を感じるのは確かです))
The faces are different,
but I definitely sense Nagato in them.
わからん
これだけじゃ漠然としすぎじゃ。
I don't know...
This alone is too vague.
じゃあ 何か思うところは
あるんすね？
But there's something?
ペインのことで わかっとることは
もう話したのう。
I've already told you
what I know about Pain.
死んでも生き返るようなヤツじゃ。
Even if he dies,
he can resurrect himself.
憶測だけでは なんとも言えんし➡
So I can't say just from speculations.
この状態で ペインを相手にするのは
危険じゃ。
Under such conditions,
taking Pain on is too dangerous.
ちゃんと謎を解かにゃいけん。
We must uncover all his secrets first.
他の情報のほうは どうなんです？
検屍と尋問。
What about the other sources
of information?
How are the autopsy and
interrogation coming along?
(サクラ)その２つは
まだ時間がかかるみたい。
It looks like they will take
more time.
Like how long?
かかるって どんくらい？
それはまだ
なんとも 言えないわね。
I can't say.
Oh, come on!
We can't be wasting time right now!
なんだよ そりゃ！
時間かけてチンタラやってる場合かよ。
尋問はともかく 検屍は➡
Interrogation aside,
an autopsy requires minute cell
and tissue analyses!
細胞や組織から検出したものを➡
丁寧に分析解析していくものなの。
どうしたって時間がかかる。
These things take time!
早くても１週間はかかるだろうな。
It'll be a week at the soonest.
そんなに かかんのかよ…。
That long...?
まぁ うずまき君
そんなにガッカリしないで。
Now, Uzumaki...
Don't be so disappointed.
じゃあ この件 どうするんすか？
五代目。
So what should we do, Lady Hokage?
検屍は シズネが担当している。
Shizune is heading up the autopsy...
いつもよりは早いだろうが
待つより他にないな。
It should be quicker than usual.
Still, we have no choice but to wait.
直接 行って
せかしてくるってばよ。
I'll go and make them speed it up.
こらナルト テメエ シズネ先輩のジャマしたら
私が許さないわよ！
Naruto! You get in
Master Shizune's way,
and I'll give you a beating!
エロ仙人の仇は オレが討つ。
I will avenge Pervy Sage!
じっとなんて
してらんねえんだよ。
I can't just sit around doing nothing!
じゃが ナルトちゃんよ
今 暗号が解読できたところで➡
But Naruto-boy...
Even if we decoded the message,
it has nothing to do with you.
お前には何の関係もないじゃろう。
そりゃ どういうことだってばよ？
Just what do you mean by that?!
どっちにしろ 今のお前では
絶対に ペインには勝てりゃあせん。
In any case, at this point,
you couldn't beat Pain.
なんだと!?
なら 何か？
What?!
Tell me. Even Jiraiya-boy
couldn't beat this opponent.
自来也ちゃんが
勝てなかった相手に➡
勝つ自信があるというのか え？
Are you saying you're confident
you can?
それは…。
Well...
今のナルトちゃんじゃあ➡
If you were to fight him now,
you'd die a senseless death.
ペインと戦っても
ムダ死にするだけじゃ。
それじゃあ じいちゃん仙人は➡
Then Geezer Sage,
are you telling me
エロ仙人の仇を
このまま見過ごせってのか！
to forget about avenging
the Pervy Sage?
そんなことは言っとりゃあせん。
No such thing.
ここに呼ばれたのは
ちょうど よかった。
Being asked to come was
quite opportune.
わしも ちょうど
ナルトちゃんを迎えに行こうかと➡
I was planning on coming
to get you, Naruto-boy.
思っとったところ
じゃったからのう。
どうじゃ ナルトちゃん。
How about it, Naruto-boy?
わしのもとで
仙術の修業をせんか？
Want to train in Sage Jutsu
under my guidance?
仙術の修業？
Sage Jutsu training?
なるほど ナルトに仙術
それは いい案です。
I see...
Naruto learning Sage Jutsu.
That is a great plan.
Is Sage Jutsu really that awesome?
仙術って そんなにすごいのか？
ああ。 この里で使えるのは
自来也様だけだった。
Yes. Lord Jiraiya was the only one
capable of using it in this village.
ペインは フカサク様とシマ様を
口寄せしている自来也に勝った。
Pain defeated Jiraiya
who had summoned Lord Fukasaku
and Lady Shima.
それは 今のままでは➡
What that means is...
木ノ葉の里の誰も
ヤツに勝てないことを意味している。
At this point, no one in
the Leaf Village can defeat Pain.
わしも悔しいんじゃ。
I am just as mortified...
弟子である自来也ちゃんの仇は
討ちたい。
I, too, want to avenge the death
of my student Jiraiya-boy.
それをできるのは ナルトちゃん
お前だけじゃと思っとる。
I believe that the only one who
can do that is you, Naruto-boy.
オレが？
Me...?
自来也ちゃんの仇を
討ちたいんじゃろ？
You want to avenge Jiraiya-boy,
don't you?
当たり前だってばよ！
なら ついてこい！
Of course I do!
Then come with me.
妙木山で仙術の修業じゃ。
I'll train you in Sage Jutsu
at Mount Myoboku.
自来也ちゃんに
叩き込んだことを➡
Everything that I drove
into Jiraiya-boy,
全部 ナルトちゃんにも
叩き込んでやる！
I will do the same with you.
それで ホントに
ペインに勝てるんだろうな？
Will it let me win against Pain?!
それは わからん。
ナルトちゃん次第じゃ。
That I can't guarantee.
It all depends on you, Naruto-boy.
ええかの？ 綱手。
もちろんです。
Is that fine with you, Tsunade?
Of course...
ナルト 行ってこい。
Naruto, go.
仙術の修業は
想像以上に厳しいぞ。
Sage Jutsu training is more rigorous
than you can ever imagine.
やるかい？
エロ仙人にも できたことだろ？
Are you up to it?
Pervy Sage did it, right?
だったら オレだって負けねえ。
やってやる！
Then I can't lose to him! I'll do it!
《託された弟子 予言の子か》
An entrusted student...
The Child of Prophecy.
よう言うた！
Nicely said!
じゃあ 行くじゃわい。
Then, let us go.
ナルトちゃん 挨拶せえ。
Naruto-boy, say your goodbyes.
行ってくるってばよ。
シカマル 暗号を頼んだぜ。
I'm off.
I'm counting on you with
the code, Shikamaru.
こっちは気にすんな。
Don't worry about us.
検屍と尋問の結果が出しだい
連絡します。
I will contact you
the moment the results of the autopsy
and interrogation are in.
連絡ガエルを残しておく。
何かあったら ソイツに託せ。
I will leave
the messenger frog behind.
If there's anything,
give it to him.
はい。
Yes sir.
ナルト がんばってね。
おっす！
Good luck, Naruto!
Right!
よっしゃ！ 出発だ！
All right! Let's go!
ところで妙木山って どっち？
By the way,
which way is Mount Myoboku?
大丈夫かしら コイツで…。
Can we really trust this guy?
(フカサク)歩いたら １か月はかかる。
It takes a month to
get there on foot.
It's also known as
Maze Mountain.
迷いの山と呼ばれとって➡
秘密のルートを知らんかったら
絶対にたどり着けん。
If you don't know the secret route,
you won't be able to get there.
行くだけで そんな大変なのか…。
It's hard just to get there, eh?
ナルトちゃんよ。
Naruto-boy...
お前は
すでに ガマとの契約済みじゃ。
You already signed
a binding contract with us toads.
そんな心配はいらん。
There's no need to worry.
あっ それ！
Hey! That's the...
では この子は預かるけんの。
Well then, I'll be borrowing this boy.
よろしくお願いします。
Please take care of him.
でも 心配いらないって…。
消えた！
But what do you mean,
there's no need to worry?
He disappeared?
逆口寄せだ。
へえ。
It's a Reverse Summoning.
Wow...
そちらも頼んだけんの。
Good luck on your end too.
All right!
よし 我々も 自来也の残した
情報解読に専念するぞ！
Let's concentrate on figuring
out the data Jiraiya left us.
了解っす。
Roger.
《大ガマ仙人の予言とやらに
自来也が本を書くと出たこと。
The fact that the Great Lord Elder
prophesied Jiraiya writing those books...
それは この暗号を伝えるための
ものだったのかもしれない。
It may have been intended
to enable him
to eventually leave
the encrypted message.
Meaning the prophecy may all be real.
だとすると その予言とやらは
本当なのかもな。
そして うずまきナルト
まさしく あの子が予言の子か》
In which case, Naruto Uzumaki...
He truly is the Child of Prophecy...
どこだ ここ？
Where...are we?
じいちゃん仙人 ここは？
Geezer Sage...
What is this place?
ガマの国じゃ。
ガマの国？
The Land of Toad.
The Land of Toad?
(ガマ吉)ナルト！
ガマ吉。
Naruto!
Gamakichi!
オレが お前を口寄せしたんじゃ
ナルト。
I summoned you here, Naruto.
なるほど そういうことか。
I see... Is that how?
まずは 修業の前の
腹ごしらえじゃ ついてこい。
Before we train, we must eat.
Come along.
えっ 飯？
Food?!
(シマ)さあ たんと食いんさい。
Now, eat up! I went all out
to prepare this meal!
腕によりをかけて作ったけんね。
ほらほら 遠慮しないで
このイモムシも食ってみんさい。
Now, now... Don't be shy.
Try these caterpillars.
い いただきます。
Th-Thank you...
ぐへ～！
あ～。
Ma will have a fit if
she sees you like this.
そんな姿 見たら
母ちゃん ブチ切れるぞ。
だから ムリして
全部食ったってばよ。
I forced it all down, didn't I?!
まあ 食いもんは➡
When you're hungry,
your belly isn't choosy.
腹が減れば 選り好みもできんし
しぜんに慣れるじゃろ。
You'll get used to it in time.
《その頃には
人間じゃなくなってる気がする》
By that time...
I'll no longer be a human being.
では 早速 修業を始める。
オッス！
Now let's begin your training.
Yes sir!
まず わしが教えるのは
忍術ではなく➡
First of all, I must explain that
what I'm about to teach you
is not ninjutsu, but Sage Jutsu.
仙術だということを
説明しとかなきゃ いけん。
説明って？
いいか。
Explain?
Listen well...
忍術が 内なるエネルギーを
利用するのに対して➡
As opposed to ninjutsu,
where you utilize your own
internal energy,
仙術は 外のエネルギーを
取り込んで利用する。
Sage Jutsu involves taking in
outside energy for your use.
外？ どういうことだ？
Outside? What do you mean?
知っとると思うが 忍術とは
己の内の精神エネルギーと➡
As you're probably aware,
Ninjutsu utilizes chakra that is molded
from one's Mental and Physical Energy.
身体エネルギーを練りこんだ
チャクラを利用するものじゃが。
仙術とは
己の内に練りこんだチャクラに➡
Sage Jutsu involves
NIN                 SAGE
taking that internally generated chakra
外からの自然エネルギ-を
更に加え 練りこんで➡
MENTAL          PHYSICAL
and adding Nature Energy
from the outside,
新たに強いチャクラを作って
利用するもの。
resulting in an even
more powerful chakra.
これにより 今までの忍術 幻術。
MENTAL     PHYSICAL     NATURE
And that leads to all
your ninjutsu, genjutsu,
更には 体術までもが
大幅にパワーアップする。
and even your taijutsu getting
a real power boost.
内からの精神エネルギーと 身体エネルギー
そして 外からの自然エネルギー。
Mental and Physical Energy
within oneself,
and Nature Energy from the outside.
この３つのエネルギーを練りこんだ
チャクラから発動する術や➡
Jutsu and techniques born
from the chakra
created by these three combined energies
is what's known as Sage Jutsu.
技のことを 仙術と呼ぶ。
う～ん。
Hmm...
ようするにじゃな
ソフトクリームのチョコバニラ味に➡
Look at it this way...
If you add mint flavor to
chocolate-vanilla ice cream,
ミント味まで加えたら
さらに うまくなる感じじゃ。
then it tastes even better.
That makes it more confusing, Gamakichi!
(フカサク)
余計わかりにくいわい ガマ吉。
ああ そういうことね！
Oh... I get it!
今ので わかったんかい。
ヘヘッ。 ナルトは こういうヤツじゃ。
You understood that analogy?
That's the kind of guy Naruto is.
その自然エネルギーってのは
ようするに なんだってばよ？
So what's this Nature Energy
really about?
己の外 大気と
大地に存在するエネルギーのことじゃ。
Energy that is external to you.
The energy that exists in
the atmosphere and the terrain.
大気と大地… はあ。
Atmosphere and terrain... Okay...
ようするに 空気と地面じゃ。
あっ そういうこと。
As in, the air and in the ground.
Oh, is that what he meant?
ええい 口ばかりじゃ なんじゃ。
Bah! Enough words. I will show you.
そろそろ やってみせようかいの。
このあたりでええじゃろう。
This should be good enough.
おお さすがフカサク様じゃ。
Wow! Lord Fukasaku is amazing!
Look at him gather all
that Nature Energy!
どんどん自然エネルギーが
集まってくる。
Where? Where?!
えっ どこ どこ？
(ガマ吉)すげえ。
Oh, wow...
うお～！
も 持ち上げた！
H-He lifted it!
ど どうじゃ… これが➡
How about that?
This is the power of
Nature Energy-enhanced Sage Jutsu.
自然のエネルギーを取り込んだ
仙術の力じゃ。
でも 何やったか
わかんなかった。
But I don't know what you did...
I only saw you weave a sign
at the beginning.
ただ じいちゃん仙人が
印をしただけにしか。
そりゃそうじゃ。
Well, naturally.
Right now, you're not yet able
to sense Nature Energy, Naruto-boy.
今のナルトちゃんじゃ
自然エネルギーは感じとれん。
So it's impossible for you to absorb it.
つまり 己に取り込むのも ムリじゃ。
じゃあ どうやって？
Then how do I do it?
自然と一体になるのじゃ。
You must become one with nature!
一体？
Become one...?
ようするに
死ねっちゅうことじゃ。
As in, you have to die.
え？
What?
Naruto engages in Sage Jutsu training
at Mount Myoboku.
Being much different from ninjutsu,
(ガジル)てめえも 時計の部品を
探しにきたのか？
Naruto struggles with
the training.
(サミュエル)君たちとは初対面だね。
Fukasaku then reveals what
it takes to become a Sage.
名乗っておこうか。
僕は サミュエル。
(レビィ)あんたが
ナツたちの言ってたエクシード。
Encouraged by the path taken
by his master,
Naruto shows he has the guts
to never give up.
そう レギオン隊の頭脳と
呼ばれているのは この僕さ。
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"The First Challenge"